Sometimes it feels like the universe is just messing with you.
有时候似乎全世界都在捉弄你
稍后再做解释
I have up on screen here a sequence of computations
现在屏幕上有一串式子
and don't worry, in a moment we're going to unpack and visualize
别担心  我们待会就逐条解读、描绘每条式子的内涵
what each one is really saying.
What I want you to notice is how the sequence follows
请各位观众注意  这一串式子
a very predictable, if random seeming pattern,
都符合一个意料之外  情理之中的模式
and how each computation happens to equal π.
它们都恰好等于 π
And if you are just messing around
如果你出于某种原因
evaluating these on a computer for some reason,
正利用电脑求这些式子的值
you might think that this was a pattern that would go on forever.
你或许会认为将会一直如此
But it doesn't.
但结果不然
At some point, it stops and instead of equaling π,
在某个点上  这种规律不再成立
you get a value which is just barely, barely less than π.
你求得的值只比 π 小一点点点
翻译   畏狐之狐  ksyx  NetaP495L
校对  saniac  ZSC  ksyx  NetaP495L  时间轴  NetaP495L
Alright, let's dig into what's going on here.
好吧  让我们探讨一下这种现象
The main character in the story today is the function sin of X divided by X.
今天的故事主角是函数 sin(x)/x
This actually comes up commonly enough in math and engineering
这个函数在数学和工程上实在是太常用了
that it gets its own name, "sinc"
它有个专门的名字叫 sinc
and the way you might think about it
你可以这样想象它的图像
is by starting with a normal oscillating sin curve
起初是一列正常的正弦波
and then sort of squishing it down
然后将其乘以 1/X
as you get far away from zero by multiplying it by 1 over X
把远离零点的图像压扁
and the astute among you might ask about what happens at X equals 0
聪明的观众或许会问  当 X 等于零时会发生什么
如果x=0呢？
since when you plug that in, it looks like dividing zero by zero
因为如果将其代入  表达式看起来是零除以零
三明治定理!
and then the even more astute among you may fresh out of a calculus class
更聪明的宝子们  或许刚上完微积分课
could point out that for values closer and closer to zero,
可以指出  当自变量趋近于 0 时
the function gets closer and closer to one.
函数值趋近于 1
So, if we simply redefine the sinc function at 0 to equal 1,
所以我们只要将 0 处的函数值定义为 1
you get a nice continuous curve.
就能获得一个漂亮的连续曲线
All of that is a little by the by
上面有点跑题了
because the thing we actually care about
我们关心的其实是这条曲线在 −∞ 到 ∞ 上的积分
is the integral of this curve from -∞ to ∞.
Which you think of as meaning the area between the curve and the X axis,
也就是说  这条曲线和 X 轴之间所夹的面积
or more precisely the signed area.
确切地说  带符号面积
Meaning you add all the area
首先将所有 X 轴上方的面积相加
bound by the positive parts of the graph in the X axis
and you subtract all of the parts
然后减去所有 X 轴下方的部分
found by the negative parts of the graph and the X axis.
Like we saw at the start,
如我们在开头所见
it happens to be the case that this evaluates to be exactly π,
它的值正好是 π
which is nice and also a little weird
看起来很漂亮  也有些诡异
真漂亮！
但为什么呀？
and it's not entirely clear how you would approach this
用微积分的基本工具并不容易得出这个结果
with the usual tools of calculus.
我将在最后
用到这个技巧
Towards the end of the video, I'll share the trick for how you would do this.
在视频最后  我会展示怎样计算这个积分
但首先...
Progressing on with the sequence I opened with,
接着看开头给出的序列的下一项
the next step is to take a copy of the sinc function where you plug in X/3,
下一步是先复制一份代入 X/3 时 sinc 函数的值
which will basically look like the same graph
看起来就像是同一张图
but stretched out horizontal by a factor of three.
在水平方向上拉伸到了原来的三倍
When we multiply these two functions together,
再将这两个函数相乘
we get a much more complicated wave
就得到了一个更复杂的波形
whose mass seems to be more concentrated towards the middle
它与 X 轴所夹的面积看起来更加集中
面积改变了，
对吧？
and with any usual functions, you would expect
如果是什么别的函数  你或许会认为面积改变了
this completely changes the area.
You can't just randomly modify an integral like this
像这样随意改变一个积分  很难使得结果不变
and expect nothing to change.
So already, it's a little bit weird that
现在开始变得奇怪了：
this result also equals π, that nothing has changed.
积分的结果仍然等于 π   没有发生变化
That's another mystery you should add to your list.
这是你应该记下的另一个疑点
又一个π，但为什么呀？
And the next step in the sequence was to take
序列中的下一项是
an even more stretched out version of this sinc function by a factor of 5,
将 sinc 函数拉伸到原来的五倍
multiply that by what we already have
再乘以上一次迭代的结果
and again, look at the signed area underneath the whole curve,
再看看曲线下方的带符号面积  仍然是 π
which again equals π.
And it continues on like this; with each iteration,
以此类推  每一次迭代中
we stretch out by a new odd number
图像都被拉伸  比例为某奇数
and multiply that into what we have.
再乘以前面的结果
One thing you might notice is how except that the input X equals 0,
你或许会注意到  除 X=0 处以外
every single part of this function
这个函数上的每个点
is progressively getting multiplied by something that's smaller than one.
每次迭代都会乘上一个小于 1 的值
So you would expect
所以你会主张
as the sequence progresses for things to get squished down more and more
随着这个序列继续延伸  函数会进一步被纵向压缩
and if anything, you would expect the area to be getting smaller.
当然  面积也就随之变小
Eventually, that is exactly what happens.
最终  这确实发生了
But what's bizarre is that it stays so stable for so long
但很奇怪的是  它在如此长的时间内能保持不变
and of course, more pertinently, that when it does break at the value 15
更值得一提的是  当 15 打破这种规律的时候
it does so by the tiniest tiny amount.
计算结果与 π 的差异几乎微不足道
And before you go thinking this is the result of some numerical error,
你或许会认为这是由于数值误差
maybe because we're doing something with floating point arithmetic,
只是因为我们在做浮点运算
if you work this out more precisely,
但如果你求出这个式子的精确值
here is the exact value of that last integral,
也就是这个值
which is a certain fraction of π
是 π 的分数倍
where the numerator and the denominator are absurd.
其中分子和分母看起来都荒诞不经
They're both around 400 billion billion billion.
足足有大约46穰
穰：中国传统大数单位，
在万进系统下等于10²⁸即“万亿亿亿”
So, this pattern was described in a paper
这种规律被写进了一篇论文中
by a father-son pair: Jonathan and David Borwein, which is very fun,
作者是一对父子档  乔纳森·博温和大卫·博温
and they mentioned how when a fellow researcher
他们提到  当一位同事
was computing these integrals using a computer algebra system,
用计算机代数系统（CAS）计算这些积分时
he assumed that this had to be some kind of bug!
他认为这一定是系统出了 bug
But it's not a bug, it is a real phenomenon.
但这不是 bug   这是一个真实存在的现象
And it gets weirder than that actually -
事实上它可以会变得更奇怪
if we take all these integrals and include yet another factor 2cos(x)
如果我们给这些积分都乘上一个 2cos(x)
which again, you would think changes their values entirely -
你肯定又以为结果会变
图几乎没有变化
you can't just randomly multiply new things into an intergral like this,
毕竟，积分式里怎么能随便乘东西呢
it continues to equal π for much much longer
但它的结果居然还是 π  甚至持续了更久
and it's not until you get to the number 113 that it breaks.
直到达到 113   这种规律才被打破
And when it breaks,
这时真实值与 π 之间的差异小到难以想象
一个我的计算机无法在
合理时间内计算的极小的正数
it's by the most puny absolutely subtle amount that you could imagine.
这到底是
为什么？
So, the natural question is - what on earth is going on here?
接下来  很自然的问题是  这到底是为什么
And luckily there actually is a really satisfying explanation for all this.
幸运的是  这里有一个非常令人满意的解释
The way I think I'll go about this
我将通过迂回的方式告诉你们为什么
一个简化的类比
is to show you a phenomenon that first looks completely unrelated
首先我会展示一个现象  看起来毫无瓜葛
but it shows a similar pattern
但是出现了类似的规律
where you have a value that stays really stable until you get to number 15
同样有个一直稳定不变的值  直到 15
and then it falters by just a tiny amount.
然后同样出现了极小的差值
And then after that, I'll show why this seemingly unrelated phenomenon
然后  我会告诉你为什么这个貌似无关的现象
从类比延伸来解释
is secretly the same as all our integral expressions but in disguise.
居然跟我们的积分式完全一致，只是换了副嘴脸
滑动窗口平均值
So, turning our attention to what seems completely different -
现在  让我们把目光从原来的问题上移开
consider a function that I'm going to be calling rect(x)
考虑一个我称为 rect(x) 的函数
which is defined to equal 1 if the input is between -1/2 and 1/2
当输入在 -1/2 和 1/2 之间时  它的取值恒为 1
and otherwise it's equal to 0.
否则为 0
So, the function is this boring step basically.
就是这个无趣的阶梯函数
This will be the first in a sequence of function that we define,
这将是我们定义的函数列的第一项
函数列中
的第一项
so I'll call it f₁(x)
因此我将其记为 f₁(x)
and each new function in our sequence is going to be
我们的序列中的每个新函数
a kind of moving average of the previous function.
都定义为前一个函数在某个滑动窗口内的均值
So, for example, the way the second iteration will be defined
例如  第二个函数的定义如下
is to take this sliding window whose width is 1/3
取这个宽度为 1/3 的窗口
and for a particular input X, when the window is centred at that input X,
它的中心在输入 X 的位置上
the value in my new function drawn below
新函数的值  如下图所示
is defined to be equal to the average value
被定义为第一个函数
这个窗口的平均值
of the first function above inside that window.
在这个窗口中的平均值
So, for example when the window is far enough to the left,
比如  现在这个窗口在左侧
every value inside it is zero,
里面的所有值都是零
so the graph on the bottom is showing zero.
因此下面的图像里对应的点为 0
As soon as that window starts to go over the plateau a little bit,
一旦窗口开始攀爬“台地”
the average value is a little more than zero
平均值就会稍大于零
and you see that in the graph below.
在下面的图中  你也可以观察到这一点
And notice that when exactly half the window is over that plateau at one
注意  当正好一半的窗口里函数值全为 1
and half of it is at zero,
另一半全为 0 时
the corresponding value in the bottom graph is one half
下面的图中对应的值为 1/2
and you get the point.
现在你应该懂了
The important thing I want you to focus on
请你留意一下这里的重点：
is how when that window is entirely in the plateau above
当上面整个窗口都处于值恒为 1 的平稳段时
where all the values are one,
then the average value is also one,
下面得到的均值也是 1
so we get this plateau on our function at the bottom.
所以下面这个函数就有了这样一段平稳段
Let's call this bottom function f₂(x)
如果我们把下面这个函数叫做 f₂(x)
and what I want you to think about
我想让你思考一下
is the length of the plateau for that second function.
下面这个平稳段的长度
How wide it should be?
它有多长呢
If you think about it for a moment,
稍加思考就会发现
the distance between the left edge of the top plateau
上下两个函数的平稳段  左边界的距离
and the left edge of the bottom plateau
will be exactly half of the width of the window. So, half of one third.
正好是窗口宽度 1/3 的一半
And similarly on the right side,
而对右边来说也一样
the distance between the edges of the plateaus is half of the window width.
两个函数右边界的距离也是窗口宽度的一半
So, overall, it's one minus that window width, which is one minus a third.
两边合起来  答案就是1减去窗口宽度  即1-1/3
The value we're going to be computing,
我们接下来要算的这个
the thing that will look stable for a while before it breaks
一开始看上去稳定  而再往后就开始改变的值
is the value of this function at the input zero,
正是这个函数在 0 处的取值
which in both of these iterations is equal to one
例如在这两个函数里都是 1
because it's inside that plateau.
因为 0 都处在这段平稳段里
For the next iteration,
下一轮迭代会计算 f₂(x) 的滑动平均值
we're going to take a moving average of that last function
but this time with the window whose width is one fifth.
但是窗口宽度只有 1/5 个单位
It's kind of fun to think about why as you slide around this window,
你可以琢磨一下  为何滑动窗口从左到右走一遍
you get a smooth out version of the previous function
得到的新函数会比原函数更光滑
and again, the significant thing I want you to focus on
但我想让你关注的重点依旧是
is how when that window is entirely inside the plateau of the previous function,
窗口在什么时候  完全处于原函数的平稳段上
then, by definition, the bottom function is going to equal one.
因为按照定义  此时下面的函数值等于 1
This time, the length of that plateau on the bottom
而这次下面这个函数的这个平稳段
will be the length of the previous one, 1-1/3
长度则是前一个函数平稳段的长度 1-1/3
minus the window width, 1/5th.
再减去窗口的宽度 1/5
The reasoning is the same as before -
原因和之前一样
in order to go from the point where
要从“窗口中点在平稳段左端点”的位置
the middle of the window is on that top plateau
to where the entirety of the window is inside that plateau
走到“整个窗完全进入平稳段里”的地方
is half the window width
正好是半个窗口的长度
and likewise on the right side.
右半边也一样
And once more, the value to record
而我们要记下来的
is the output of this function when the input is zero.
则是这个函数在自变量为 0 时的取值
Which again, is exactly one.
还是 1
The next iteration is a moving average with the window width of 1/7 -
再往下一轮  我们用 1/7 的窗口宽度来计算滑动平均
the plateau gets smaller by that 1/7.
那这样平稳段也就短了 1/7
Doing one more iteration with 1/9, the plateau gets smaller by that amount.
再用 1/9 的窗口宽度迭代一轮  平稳段也缩短了 1/9
And as we keep going, the plateau gets thinner and thinner.
随着轮数逐渐增加  平稳段越来越短
And also, notice how just outside of the plateau,
此外  在平稳段稍微往外的位置
the function is really really close to one,
函数值会非常非常接近 1
because it's always been the result of an average
因为这是不断把平稳段的 1
between the plateau at one and the neighbours,
和它十分十分接近 1 的邻近值
which themselves are really really close to one.
不断取平均的结果
The point at which all of this breaks
f(0)=1 的规律被打破的时间
is once we get to the iteration
是在我们迭代到
where we're sliding a window with width 1/15th across the whole thing.
用 1/15 的窗口宽度滑动时
At that point, the previous plateau
到了这一轮  上面的平稳段
is actually thinner than the window itself.
已经短于窗口本身了
So, even at the input X=0,
因此  即使自变量x=0
this moving average have to be ever so slightly smaller than one.
滑动平均还是会比 1 小那么一点点
And the only thing that's special about the number 15 here is that
而 15 这个数的特殊之处  无非在于
as we keep adding the reciprocals of these odd fractions -
当我们累加奇数的倒数和
1/3 plus 1/5th plus 1/7th, on and on,
也就是 1/3+1/5+1/7 这样加下去时
it's once we get to 1/15th that that sum grows to be bigger than one
加到 1/15 这个和刚好比 1 大
and in the context of our shrinking plateaus,
从缩短平稳段的视角来看
having started with a plateau of width one,
原本宽度为 1 的平稳段
it's now shrunk down so much that it will disappear entirely.
到这里就沦落到渣都不剩了
The point is, with this as a sequence of functions
总的来说就是  对于这串
that we've defined by seemingly random procedure,
看上去定义得很随便的函数序列
if I ask you to compute the values of all of these functions at the input zero,
如果计算每个函数在x=0处的函数值
you get a pattern which initially looks stable,
会得到一个  最开始很稳定的规律
it's one, one, one, one, one, one, one
算出来全是 1 1 1 1 1 1 1
but by the time we get to the eighth iteration,
但到第八轮迭代时
it falls short ever so slightly, just barely.
得出的结果就会比 1 小就那么一丁点
This is analogous,
这是不是很像
and I claim more than just analogous to the integrals we saw earlier,
(其实不止是像而已) 之前提到的那个积分的问题
where you have a stable value at π, π, π, π, π
一开始有一串稳定的 π π π π π
until it falls short just barely.
但最后会比 π 小那么一点点
And as it happens, this constant from our moving average process
而且  我们通过反复算滑动平均得到的这个
这个常数
that's ever so slightly smaller than one
比 1 小那么一丁点的数
is exactly the factor that sits in front of π in our series of integrals.
恰好是积分问题里  在π前面的系数
相同常数
So, the two situations aren't just qualitatively similar,
所以  这两个情形不只是定性的相近
they're quantitatively the same as well.
而是定量的相同
And when it comes to the case
而如果对被积函数多乘个 2cosX
where we add the 2 cosine of X term inside the integral,
which cause the pattern to last a lot longer before it broke down,
就得迭代更多轮  才能打破积分为π的规律
一个我的计算机无法在
合理时间内计算的极小的正数
in the analogy, what that will correspond to
如果放回类比的情况里  就对应了
is the same setup
其它条件不变   但平稳段伸得更长了
but where the function we start with has an even longer plateau -
stretching from x = -1 up to 1, meaning its length is 2.
一直从 -1 到 1 也就是长度为 2
So, as you do this repeated moving average process,
这样在滑动平均时
eating into it with smaller and smaller windows,
能蚕食高原的窗口越来越小
it takes a lot longer for them to eat into the whole plateau.
要消化掉整个高原  就需要多得多的迭代次数
More specifically, the relevant computation is to ask -
更具体点  我们要去计算
how long do you have to add these reciprocals of odd numbers
要加多少项奇数的倒数
until that sum becomes bigger than two?
结果才能比 2 大呢
And it turns out that you have to go until you hit the number 113,
答案是要加到 1/113
Which will correspond to the fact that
这也对应着
一个我的计算机无法在
合理时间内计算的极小的正数
the integral pattern there continues until you hit 113.
积分为π的规律  要一直到113才被打破
And by the way, I should emphasize that
另外我要强调的是
there is nothing special about these reciprocals of odd numbers;
这些 1/3 1/5 1/7 的奇数倒数
并不特别
one third, one fifth, one seventh -
也并没有什么特别的
that just happens to be the sequence of values
只是因为刚好 Borwein 的论文里用了这个数列
highlighted by the Borweins in their paper
that made the sequence mildly famous in nerd circles.
它也就在理工宅的圈子中火起来了
并不特别
More generally,
一般地说
we could be inserting any sequence of positive numbers into those sinc functions
我们可以在sinc函数里插入任意正数列
and as long as the sum of those numbers is less than one,
只要和小于 1
our expression will equal π,
这个积分的结果就是 π
but as soon as they become bigger than one,
而当这些和超过 1 以后
our expression drops a little below π
结果就会比 π 小那么一点了
and if you believe me that there's an analogy with these moving averages,
如果你相信我它和滑动平均是同理的问题
you can hopefully see why.
你就应该已经知道为什么了
为什么这两种式子有关联呢？
But of course, the burning question is
但这里更为关键的问题是
why on earth should these two situations have anything to do with each other?
究竟为什么这两种式子会有关联呢
From here, the argument does bring in two mildly heavy bits of machinery,
而这就需要引入两个稍微重量级的工具
傅里叶变换
namely Fourier Transforms and convolutions.
傅里叶变换和卷积
傅里叶变换
卷积
And the way I'd like to go about this is to spend the remainder of this video
这个视频接下来的部分
giving you a high level sense of how the argument will go
我想让你在不必熟知这两个工具的情况下
首先，我们来进行高层次的理解
without necessarily assuming you're familiar with either of those two topics
对它们有着关联的原因有个高层次的理解
and then to explain why the details are true
在后续专门讲卷积的视频中
卷积
定理
in a video that's dedicated to convolutions.
我会进一步解释细节
In particular something called The Convolution Theorem
尤其是卷积定理为何成立
since it's incredibly beautiful
这个定理非常美妙
and it's useful well beyond this specific very esoteric question.
而且实用之广  远超出这个非常偏门的问题
画图展示两者联系
To start, instead of focusing on this function sin(x)/x,
首先  我们不去考虑 sin(x)/x 这个函数本身
where we want to show why the signed area underneath its curve is equal to π,
例如为什么曲线下方的带号面积是 π
we'll make a simple substitution where we replace the input x with π*x,
而是先把 x 替换成 πx
which has the effect of squishing the graph horizontally by a factor of π
也就把整个函数图像横向收缩了 π 倍
and so, the area gets scaled down by a factor of π,
面积也缩小了 π 倍
meaning our new goal is to show
于是我们要问的也就变成了
why this integral on the right is equal to exactly one.
为什么右边这个积分结果正好为 1
By the way, in some engineering context,
顺带一提  有时候在工程上
people use the name "sinc" to refer to this function with the π on the inside
一些人会用 sinc 来指代积分项里这个带 π 的函数
since it's often very nice to have a normalized function,
因为经过归一化的函数更方便使用
meaning the area under it is equal to one.
“归一化”指曲线下的带号面积为 1
The point is, showing this integral on the right
重点是  证明右边这个积分
is exactly the same thing as showing the integral on the left,
跟证明左边这个积分  完全是一码事
it's just a change of variables.
只是用了换元法
And likewise for all of the other ones in our sequence,
同理  对于序列中的其他积分式
go through each of them, replace the X with the π times X.
我们把每一个式子里的x都换成πx
这些算式...
...(在某种意义上)与它们等价
And from here, the claim is that
这时我们要证的是
all these integrals are not just analogous to the moving average examples
这些积分跟“滑动窗口均值”的联系绝不只是类比
but that both of these are two distinct ways of computing exactly the same thing.
两条不同的路子  根本就是在计算同一个东西
我们必须揭示的是
And the connection comes down to the fact that
两者的联系  归根就是因为：
this sinc function or the engineer sinc function with the π on the inside
sinc函数，或者说工程师含π的sinc函数
is related to the rect function
跟rect函数有所关联
using what's known as a Fourier Transform.
这要借助所谓的“傅里叶变换”
Now if you've never heard of a Fourier Transform,
如果你从未听过这个概念
这意味着？
there are a few other videos on this channel all about it.
我们频道有几期视频就是介绍傅里叶变换的
傅里叶变换
The way it's often described is that if you want to break down a function
我们一般这样来描述：如果你想把周期函数
as the sum of a bunch of pure frequencies
分解成“许多纯正弦波”之和
or in the case of an infinite function,
或者把定义域无限长的函数
a continuous integral of a bunch of pure frequencies,
分解成“无数纯正弦波”的连续积分
the Fourier Transform will tell you
傅里叶变换可以告诉你  每个组分的强度和相位
all the strength and phases for all those constituent parts.
But all you really need to know here is that
但你现在只需要知道
is something which takes in one function and spits out a new function
向它输入一个函数  它会输出一个新函数
and you often think of it as kind of
你可以把它想像成是
rephrasing the information of your original function in a different language.
将你函数里蕴含的信息  换一种语言重新表述出来
Like you're looking at it from a new perspective.
也就是在用新的视角去看待它
我们必须揭示的是
For example, like I said,
举个例子
this sinc function written in this new language
如果对sinc函数作傅里叶变换
where you take a Fourier Transform
用另一种语言重述
looks like our top hat rect function.
它就成了rect函数里的“高原”部分
And vice versa by the way,
其实反之亦然
this is a nice thing about Fourier Transforms
关于Y轴对称的偶函数  有一个好处
for functions that are symmetric about the Y axis, that is its own inverse.
傅里叶变换和逆变换一样 (都是实值偶函数)
and actually the slightly more general fact that we'll need to show
我们需要说明的更一般化的第一件事实是
is how when you transform the stretched out version of our sinc function
如果你变换这个拉伸后的sinc函数
where you stretch it horizontally by a factor of K,
水平方向拉伸倍数为K
what you get is a stretched and squished version of this rect function.
你就得到了原rect函数的拉宽压扁版本
But of course, all of these are just meaningless words and terminology
当然  这些语句和术语本身无用
unless you can actually do something upon making this translation.
除非你能让这种新视角发挥用处
傅立叶变换后的频域
And the real idea behind
傅里叶变换之所以如此有用  真正原因在于
why Fourier Transforms are such a useful thing for math
is that when you take statements and questions about a particular function
若已知某函数的信息  你拿着关于该函数的问题
and then you look at what they correspond to
然后你想看看  在变换过的函数里
with respect to the transformed version of that function,
这些陈述和问题会对应什么
those statements and questions
那么  在新的语言里  它们经常会彻底“改头换面”
often look very very different in this new language,
and sometimes it makes the questions a lot easier to answer.
有时候会让问题化难为易
我们必须揭示的是
For example, one very nice little fact,
就拿有意思的一点来说
another thing on our list of things to show,
也是我们要说明的第二件事实：
is that if you want to compute the integral of some function from -∞ to ∞,
如果你想计算某个函数从−∞到∞的积分
this signed area under the entirety of its curve,
在这整个曲线下的带符号面积
it's the same thing as simply evaluating
就等同于求出
the Fourier Transformed version of that function at the input zero.
“傅里叶变换后的函数”在0处的值
This is a fact that will actually just pop right out of the definition
其实  套用定义就能直接得出这一点
and representative of a more general vibe that
但它也代表了更广泛的性质：
every individual output of the Fourier Transform function on the right
右边由傅里叶变换函数得出的每个单独点
corresponds to some kind of global information
都代表了原函数的某种全局信息
about the original function on the left.
In our specific case, it means if you believe me
具体放在我们的例子里：如果你相信我说的
that this sinc function and the rect function
这里的sinc函数和rect函数
are related with the Fourier Transform like this,
互为对方的傅里叶变换
it explains the integral which is otherwise a very tricky thing to compute
那么  原先老难算的积分值  现在就小菜一碟了
because it's saying all that signed area
因为左边的整个有向面积
is the same thing as evaluating rect at zero
就成了计算rect函数在0处的值
which is just one.
也就是1
但是你怎么来计算傅里叶变换呢？
Now, you could complain - surely this just moves the bump under the rug.
你可以抱怨一下——这只是掩盖了问题
Surely computing this Fourier Transform, whatever that looks like
当然  计算傅里叶变换
would be as hard as computing the original integral.
一点儿不比计算原积分要简单
But the idea is that
但这里的思想是
我们总会得到的
there's lots of tips and tricks for computing these Fourier Transforms
计算傅里叶变换时能用上很多技巧和窍门
and moreover, that when you do,
而且当你这样做的时候
it tells you a lot more information than just that integral.
它提供的信息远多于这个积分本身
You get a lot of bang for your buck out of doing the computation.
这个计算一本万利
关键事实
Now, the other key fact
第三件能解释这种联系的关键事实在于
that will explain the connection we're hunting for is that
if you have two different functions and you take their product
如果你把两个不同的函数相乘
and then you take the Fourier Transform of that product,
然后对积函数作傅里叶变换
it would be the same thing
它就等同于
as if you individually took the Fourier Transforms of your original function
先对两个函数分别作傅里叶变换
and then combined them using a new kind of operation
再用一种新的运算将二者结合
that we'll talk all about in the next video known as a Convolution.
我们会在下一期视频中谈到这种运算——卷积
Now, even though there's a lot to be explained with convolutions,
尽管对于卷积  我还需要给出更多解释
the upshot will be that in our specific case with these rectangular functions,
但结果是  在我们这个rect函数的特定情况下
taking a convolution looks just like
计算“卷积”看起来就像是
one of the moving averages that we've been talking about this whole time.
我们刚才一直在提的滑动窗口均值
Combined with our previous fact that
将其与前面提到的
integrating in one context looks like evaluating at zero in another context,
“左边是积分  换到右边就成了求0处的值”结合起来
if you believe me, that multiplying in one context
如果你相信我  在左侧体现为“乘法”的东西
corresponds to this new operation, convolutions,
在右侧  则对应这种新的“卷积”运算
which for our example you should just think of as moving averages,
在本例中  你可以把卷积当成是滑动窗口均值
乘积并求积分
that will explain why multiplying more and more of these sinc functions together
这就解释了  为什么把越来越多的sinc函数相乘
can be thought about in terms of these progressive moving averages
可以想象成这个逐步迭代的滑动均值
变换到
傅里叶频域
and always evaluating at zero,
并且总是只求0处的值
零点处的滑动窗口均值
which in turn gives a really lovely intuition
这反过来向我们直观地展现了
for why you would expect such a stable value
为什么“结果一直稳定  直到打破规律”
before eventually something breaks down
的这个事实并不出奇
as the edges of the plateau inch closer and closer to the center.
可以由“高原的边界越来越靠近中心”推出来
我们必须揭示的是
This last key fact by the way has a special name,
顺带一提  我们把最后这个关键事实
卷积定理
it's called the Convolution Theorem.
称作“卷积定理”
And again, it's something that we'll go into much more deeply.
更深入的内容依然放在下期视频里
你不解释一下为什么
这些是正确的么？
I recognize that it's maybe a little unsatisfying to end things here
我意识到这个结尾看得观众有点意犹未尽
by laying down three magical facts
我丢下三条神奇的事实
and saying "everything follows from those",
然后说“一切皆循此法”
but hopefully this gives you a little glimpse of
但我是希望  这能让你一窥
耐心一些
why powerful tools like Fourier Transforms
为什么像傅里叶变换这样的强大工具
can be so useful for tricky problems.
对这些棘手的难题这么有效
这些算式...
...(在某种意义上)与它们等价
It's a systematic way to provide a shift in perspective
这种系统化的方法扩宽了我们的视角
where hard problems can sometimes look easier.
让有些难题能变得更简单
If nothing else, it hopefully provides some motivation
至少  我希望它能成为一个契机
to learn about these beautiful things like the convolution theorem.
推动你去学习这些有趣的理论  比如卷积定理
As one more tiny teaser,
稍微剧透一下：
两个d位数
another fun consequence of this convolution theorem
卷积定理的另一个好玩的结果是
will be that it opens the doors for an algorithm
它为“大数乘积的快速算法”推开了大门
that lets you compute the product of two large numbers very quickly -
like way faster than you think should be even possible.
速度快得让人难以置信
So with that, I'll see you in the next video.
我们下期见～